







ABOUT ME

I am a Senior Interaction (IDX), User Experience (UX), User Interface (UI), and Product Designer with over 8 years of experience designing and delivering innovative and emergent experiences. I have lead user research, usability testing, prototyping, and design system efforts across multiple flagship software products.

Working in collaboration with Product Managers, Developers, Executives and Design Teams I have delivered designs that meet customer needs, user requirements, and business goals. I focus on designing and releasing highly intuitive, customer centric, modern UX/UI designs.

I finalize design documentation for software development teams, coordinate all required design revisions, and ensure that software development efforts produced the intended UX/UI for the software.

When bugs or customer enhancement requests arise I step in to retain the UX/UI integrity of the product and ensure that the fixes and enhancements fall within the product roadmap.

My specialties include Interaction Design, User Experience Design, User Interface Design, Product Design, User Centered Design (UCD), Interactive Design, Service Design, Prototyping, Wireframes, Ideation, User Flows, User Research, User Tests, User Acceptance Testing (UAT), Software as a Service (SaaS), Systems Development Life Cycle (SDLC), Usability Validation, Mobile & Desktop Applications.

EDUCATION

2016

Cooper

Interaction Design Course, User Experience Design

- · Extract behavioral patterns and insights from user research.
- Create design personas to encapsulate and communicate behavioral patterns.

2011

Utah State University

Bachelors of Fine Art, Graphic Design

- Focused on UX/UI design with a customer centric model for solving UX interactions.
- Learned multiple methods for designing, coding (HTML, CSS, JS), and prototyping UX/UI.

Associates, German Language



TECHNICAL SKILLS

Adobe XD Sketch Principle InVision Adobe Illustrator Adobe Photoshop Adobe InDesign Balsamiq Mockups HTML CSS



WORK EXPERIENCE

2015

NICE inContact | Salt Lake City, Utah

Sr. Interaction Designer August 2015 - Present **** 801.320.3200

- Lead the interaction and visual design for multiple SaaS based applications.
- Create new experiences that answer market problems and make our software a market leader.
- · Run user testing both in person and remotely.
- Work alongside product managers & engineer teams to meet both business and user needs.
- · Assist in producing style guides and interaction specification sheets for engineers.
- Design and create fully-interactive prototypes & click-throughs to better communicate user stories to executives, engineers, and users.

2012

FranklinCovey | Salt Lake City, Utah

UX Designer March 2012 – August 2015

\$ 801.817.1776

- Design and direct the UX of multiple sites, apps, and marketing micro-sites in a team environment.
- Use user stories and other data to create compelling navigation and page layout in both native and responsive web environments.
- Created a new fully responsive template system for marketing emails. This helped the marketing department be faster to market and more agile.
- Code full websites, micro-sites and marketing emails using best practices and standards.

2011

Desert Health Group | Salt Lake City, Utah

Graphic & Web Designer lune 2011 - March 2012

- Create a branding system for the over 24 facilities across the Midwest.
- Manage UI/UX for 3 corporate websites, code all updates and additions to keep sites current.
- Plan, complete and prepare all design work for both print & web for corporate office and 24 facilities.
- Created a IS enabled PDF that eased the complicated nature of RUG IV calculations for staff.

2010

Utah State University | Logan, Utah

Intern Graphic Designer August 2010 - January 2011 435.797.1351

- · Work with marketing heads, college deans, and the public relations department to determine design needs.
- · Create a new brand and all brand elements for the Swaner Preserve and EcoCenter.
- Design for both web and print media.
- Work in a team environment with the other interns to provide and receive feedback on projects.